[Music] After Tata Capital, HDB Financial Services and
LG Electronics India, the country is now set to
witness another mega listing.
Yes, now soon the fourth largest IPO of the year 2025
is going to open for subscription.  We are talking about the
IPO of ICICI Prudential AMC and meanwhile a
big question is continuously arising in the market
[Music] that will ICICI Bank also give a
big dividend to its shareholders like HDFC Bank
?  Let us
try to find the answer to this question in today's video.
[Music] We'll
also take a look at the key aspects of this IPO.  Hello,
I am Saloni Tyagi and you are watching
Mani.  ICICI PDL Asset Management Company has
launched its IPO on 8 December 2025.  The
company has fixed the price band of its IPO at
₹261 to
₹2165 per
share.  This IPO is 100% off
a sale.  That means the company is not issuing new shares.
Rather, existing investors will
sell their stake in it.  Under this offer, UK
promoter company Protential Corporation
Holdings is going to release around 4.9
crore of its shares in the market.
If this IPO is successful, the market value of the company
can reach around Rs 1.07 lakh crore, which will be
considered a big achievement for the AMC sector.
Bidding for this IPO will start from December 12, 2025
and will continue till December 16.  The
bidding for anchor investors will be on December 11,
2025.  The minimum bid lot for this IPO will be
six equity shares and thereafter
investors will be able to bid in multiples of six shares.  With
this, even small investors can easily
participate in this IPO.  Ahead of the IPO,
ICICI Bank has already increased its stake in the AMC.
ICICI Bank has now further strengthened
its hold in the company by buying an additional 2% stake in the AMC.
In this IPO,
shareholder
quota has also been kept for the existing shareholders of the bank.  That means investors of ICICI Bank will
get direct priority.   The
IPO of ICICI Prudential AMC reminds us of the
HDB Financial Services IPO that came earlier this year.
HDB's issue was worth approximately
₹1500 crore.  Of which the
OFS portion of ₹100 crore was of HDFC Bank.  When HDFC
Bank benefited from this issue, HDFC
Bank made a
big announcement for its investors.  Firstly,
1:1 bonus issue and secondly,
special dividend of ₹5 per share.  This was the
first bonus issue in the history of HDFC Bank.  And now the
question arises whether ICICI Bank AMC
will use the profits from the IPO to reward its shareholders
or will this amount be used to strengthen the company's balance sheet and
capital.
Most experts believe that anything
is possible.  But the bank's board meeting
and the upcoming quarterly results will
give a clearer picture in this regard.  Let us now take
a look at the dividend history of ICICI Bank.
In the year 2017, the bank had
given 1:10 bonus issue.  That means those holding 10 shares
got one additional share.
Earlier, the bank had done stock split in December 2014.  That
means one share was
divided into five parts.  It then split
one equity share of ₹10
into five equity shares of ₹2 each.  The bank's
September shareholding report shows that
ICICI Bank has
over 19.2 lakh retail shareholders.   At
present, i.e. on 9 December 2025, the
share of ICICI Bank is trading at around ₹1375.50.
If you have
invested in ICICI Bank, then its shareholder
quota can be a good opportunity for you to participate in the IPO.
Now whether you will participate in it
or not, please tell us in the comment section
and for more such news and updates,
stay connected with us and
keep watching Money Nine.
How will our markets open based on global signals
?  What are the news and
brokerage reports saying?  Which shares will make
money?  What to buy after the market opens?
Which stocks should be excluded from the portfolio?
How was the market's trading throughout the day?
How to prepare a strategy for tomorrow's market
?  Know the answers to all these questions
with me in Opening Buzz and Closing Buzz,
only money at these times.
Money has brought membership program Money
Prime.  Now you will have many questions in your mind.
For example, what is this Money Prime?
What are its benefits for you, the audience
?  And the big question is
how to join Money Prime?  So
we are going to give you complete information about this.
Money Prime will have three plans: Economy,
Standard and VIP.  So quickly join
Money Prime on YouTube.  To join,
visit Money's YouTube page.
Join button will be available on the home page.  Click on it.
Choose the plan of your choice and that's it.  Now you will be at the
forefront.